准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
珊瑚营怪客  上集
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
派大星
好耶  早餐
Oh, boy, breakfast
早餐不乖
Bad breakfast
老老实实给我待肚子里
You go in my tummy
你可是第一个成功逃出来的食物
You're the first food to ever escape
我向你致敬
I salute you, sir
是个信封
It's an envelope
不是很合我的口味  但也无所谓
Not my favorite flavor, but whatever
原来这信封是用来开的
It's an opening envelope
不是用来吃的
not an eating envelope
这种东西应该配个说明书才对的
These things should come with instructions
也许海绵宝宝可以帮忙
Maybe SpongeBob can help
他可是样样精通
He's good at stuff and things
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
可以帮我打开这个早餐信封吗
Can you open this breakfast envelope for me?
你也收到了早餐信封吗
You got a breakfast envelope too?
太神秘了吧
How mysterious
一起打开吧
Let's open them together
这信  鼻然不能开啊
This letter's just "snot" gonna open
可能得再使点劲才拆得开
Maybe it just needs a little extra elbow grease
手肘油
看吧
See?
我怎么说的
What'd I tell--
是我从前在珊瑚营地戴的领巾
My old Kamp Koral neckerchief?
漂亮
Neat
是我从前在珊瑚营地穿的内裤
My old Kamp Koral underwear
都已经好多年没穿过了
I haven't worn these in years
你说会不会还有谁也收到了
Say, you think anyone else got sent
珊瑚营的欢乐回忆呢
fun Kamp Koral memories?
去问问从前的室友珊迪
Let's ask our old bunkmate, Sandy
我觉得这些回忆
I think these memories
害我大脑供血不足了
are cutting off the circulation to my brain
信封
Envelope?
对了  确实有收到
Oh, yeah, I got one of those
我一打开
Opened it up
从前戴过的牙套就飞进了我嘴里
and got hit right in the kisser by my old braces
很好  大家都收到奖了
Cool, everyone got a prize
真相大白
OK, mystery solved
再见
Goodbye
先别走
Wait
你们没看过信封里的信吗
Didn't you read the letter in the envelope?
还有信
The letter?
怀念小时候无忧无虑的日子吗
"Do you miss the carefree days of your youth?
不用再烦恼了  我特地邀请你们
"Well, pine away no more, because you're invited
来珊瑚营地参加超棒团圆会
"to a killer reunion at Kamp Koral
快来重温童年  一起狂欢吧
"Come relive your childhood and party down
保证可以嗨死你
You'll just die from all the fun"
署名  X
Signed "X"
知道这个是什么意思吗
Do you know what this means?
知道
Yep
这个  指的就是特定的人或物
"This" refers to a specific person or object
还真是这么个事
Yeah, that is right
但意思也是
but it also means
我们要重返珊瑚营地了
we're going back to Kamp Koral
击掌
High five
贻贝海滩
练出肌肉
Get swole
咪
Meep?
哞
Moop?
拖
Mop
我才不要
I ain't going
回我从前办的夏令营开破烂团圆会呢
to some dumb reunion at me old summer camp
好不容易及时把那破地方关了
I barely shut that place down in time
才避免违反各种卫生法令
to avoid all those health code violations
这个半毛钱硬币我到哪都认得
I'd know this nickel anywhere
附注  眼熟不
"P.S. Look familiar?
有胆的话  就来找剩下的吧
Come and get the rest if you dare"
海神王啊
Sweet Neptune
还有地图  能带我找失踪的营地硬币
A map to me lost camp nickels
藏得特别深  连我都忘记放哪了
The ones I hid so well, even I forgot where I hid ‘em
我跟钱要团圆了
Me and me money
这团圆会倒是值得一去了
Now, that's a reunion worth attending
天啊  等不及要重返珊瑚营地了
Oh, boy, I can't wait to go back to Kamp Koral
是没错  可要怎么过去
Yeah, but how are we gonna get there?
我独轮车拿去卖了
My unicycle's in the shop
那
Well--
有了
I know
可以蹦蹦跳跳过去
We could prance
好耶
Oh, boy
我好久没蹦蹦跳跳了
I haven't pranced in ages
快上大巴就对了
Just get on the bus
对啊  大巴
Oh, yeah, the bus
确实坐大巴更合理些
Yeah, I do suppose that makes sense
您正在
驶出裤头村
等等我  兄弟们
Wait for me, dudes
因此企鹅男孩  用了双手
And that's why Barnacle Boy, with both hands
哞哞哞
Moop moop moop
你看什么看  小子
What are you looking at, boy-o?
自打夏令营你就没变过  蟹老板
You haven't changed a bit since camp, Mr. Krabs
各位营友们好
Greetings, fellow campers
我想亲自感谢
I'd like to personally thank
邀请我们参加盛大团圆会的营友
whoever invited us to the big reunion
所以是谁呢
So who was it?
不是我
Not me
好吧
Oh, well
等到了营地就知道了
We're sure to know when we get there
下一站  赚钱营地
Next stop, Kamp Money
尤金
Eugene
我是说  珊瑚营地
I mean, Kamp Koral
好耶
Yeah
还是那个珊瑚营地
Good old Kamp Koral
珊瑚营地
莫名感觉有些不一样了
It seems different somehow
这里好像改名叫册吕了
Looks like they changed the name to Ka-Ka
册             吕
不得不说  这里真的荒废了
Well, I must say, the place has really gone to pot
好像有谁
Well, I think someone
在借团圆会的名头耍我们
is pulling a fast one with this reunion
别听她的  小硬币
Don't listen to her, little nickel
马上就能找到你朋友了
We'll find your friends soon
咱就是说  这地方比我记忆中小多了
This place is, like, way smaller than I remember
不是地方小了
It's not smaller
是你长大了
You're just bigger
但是地方确实烂了不少
But it is a lot crummier
好了  玩笑开得已经够过分了
All right, I think this joke has gone far enough
大家回大巴上
Everyone, back on the bus
我们绝不留在这里
We are not staying here
不用担心
Not to worry
我去拿修理工具
I'll get the tools
把轮胎装回去
and we'll put the wheels back on
也许可以
Maybe we could just--
看来得步行过桥了
Well, looks like we're walking back across the bridge
不会吧
Oh, no
只好走老旧隧道了
We'll have to use the old tunnel
没事
That's OK
到热气球场去
To the hot air balloon field
我们被困了
We're trapped
所有出路都没了
Every way to get is gone
被困的怕是只有你们贱民才对
Maybe for the likes of you rabble
瑞吉吉尔德  执行救富行动
Regigilled, commence Operation Wealth Extraction
什么鬼东西
What in tarnation?
那是什么
What is that?
啥玩意
What is it?
等等
Wait
等一下啊
Wait, wait, wait
快点  瑞吉吉尔德
Hurry, Regigilled
看看你们把我第三爱的直升机怎么了
Look what you've done to my third-favorite helicopter
冒犯到我了
I am offended
起码没有谁受伤  对吧
At least no one got hurt, right?
营长
终于只有自己一个了
Finally alone
来找找我的财宝
Now to find me booty
来看看  向南一百步
Let's see, 100 paces south
好
OK
一二三
1, 2, 3--
给我让开  小屋
Out of my way, cabin
臭小屋
Stupid cabin
四五
4, 5
这下该怎么办  蟹老板
What should we do now, Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
谁看到尤金了
Has anyone seen Eugene?
我好像看到他
I think I saw him
胳膊底下夹着个东西走了
walk off with something under his arm
我爸要是胳膊夹着报纸就走
If my dad had a newspaper under his arm when he left
肯定好几个小时都不见踪影
we won't see him for a couple of hours
九十八
九十九
一百
叉叉表示藏宝地点
X marks the spot
找到了
Found it
现在来取走里面的财宝
Now to get what's coming to me
那声音听起来像蟹老板
That sounds like Mr. Krabs
在狂欢
having a blast
蟹老板不愧是营长
Good ol' Camp Master Krabs
太会玩了
He knows how to have fun
什么声音
What's that?
可能还有一趟接我们回去的大巴
Maybe it's another bus to take us home
海加护士
Nurse Helga
就是我
It is me
我来开团圆会了
I am here for the reunion
我错过什么了
What'd I miss?
看样子我来得刚刚好
And it looks like I got here just in time
回来  受伤的小胖
Come back, bubby with the boo-boo
看来珊瑚营地重新开张了
Looks like Kamp Koral is reopen for business
大伙们  如果非得困在这里
Well, gang, if we're gonna be stuck here
倒不如来享受下重返营地的感觉吧
we might as well enjoy being back in camp
蹦跳欢呼往日珊瑚营
Jump up and cheer for old Kamp Koral
珊瑚营地
食物做工差  味道不对劲
Where the food is bad and tastes abnormal
床上到处都是虫
The bunks are filled with bugs
树林也很不正常
And the woods are paranormal
但我们热爱珊瑚营
But we love it here in camp
所以肯定不会吵吵嚷嚷
So there'll be no quarrel
咱这都快没命了
We're gonna die out here
我都不知道咋了
I don't know what's happening
这真是我们从前的小屋吗
Is this really our old cabin?
游艇
瑞吉吉尔德  开门
Regigilled, door
如您所愿
As you wish
我的天啊
Oh, heavens
真恶心
Disgusting
无法容忍
Outrageous
我们美丽的小屋
Our beautiful cabin's
本来还是豪宅  现在变破棚子了
gone from chateau to shanty
天啊
Oh, my
瑞吉吉尔德
Regigilled
如您所愿
As you wish
这东西的疙瘩比我记忆中还要多
It's a bit lumpier than I remember
这地方闹鬼了
This place is haunted
瑞吉吉尔德
Regigilled
如您所愿
As you wish
可否还有其他吩咐
Will there be anything else?
如您所愿
As you wish
谢谢你帮忙移走直升机那玩意
Thanks for removing that helicopter thingy
可现在我肚子又空洞起来了
But now my stomach is empty again
吃的
Food
笨东西
Imbeciles
这小屋临走时本来还很干净的
This cabin was spotless when I left
我的手术刀
My scalpels
我的夹钳
My clamps
我的劈砍工具
My slashing tools
都不见了
All gone
谁在那里
Who's there?
有谁受伤了吗
Does someone have a boo-boo?
要不要海加护士治好你
Do you need Nurse Helga to put you back together?
能不能小点声
Will you please keep it down
刚刚那声很明显是狼人
That was obviously a werewolf
可现在才白天  压根没月亮
But it's daytime, and there's no moon
那就肯定是有个到处抢劫的营地怪客
Then it must be some sort of marauding camp creeper
有个更严重的问题
We have bigger problems
滑索上面没吊具
It appears there's no mechanism for zipping
那就随机应变
Then let's improvise
我屁股连续两次摔出脑震荡了
My posterior has suffered
a double cranial concussion
样子好像不太正常
It's not looking so good
不好了
Oh, no
他屁股受伤了
His butt is wiped out
多谢你了  凯文
Thank you, Kevin
我屁股不至于难看成那样
but I'm sure my butt doesn't look that bad
凯文呢
Where's Kevin?
凯文  别鬼混了
Kevin, quit goofing around
我感觉到
I've got a feeling
这附近发生了超自然现象
there's something supernatural going on around here
我也感觉得到
I've got a feeling too
屁股不舒服
in my glutes
吃的
Food
点心
Snacks
吃的
Food
点心
Snacks
是蟹老板餐车
The Krusty Kanteen
千万别骂我没尽力
Let no man say I didn't try
是谁在冲我吐水吗
Is someone blorping at me?
再非法倾倒一桶过期海霸糊就完事了
Just one more drum
of expired chum left to illegally dump
真不懂你为什么
I don't know why you
坚持要大老远过来
insisted on coming all the way out here
只为了倒点海霸糊
just to dump some chum
因为就连白痴都不会大老远过来
Because not even an idiot
would come all the way out here
嗨  痞老板
Hi, Mr. Plankton
是你啊
It's you
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
是来开派对狂欢的
We're here for the party
你没收到珊瑚营地团圆会邀请吗
Didn't you get an invite to the Kamp Koral reunion?
团圆会
Reunion?
我凭什么要去那什么破烂托儿会
Why would I go to a dumb daycare reunion?
因为我们饿了
‘Cause we're getting hungry
你先前在这当过大厨
and you were the cook here once
快给我去下厨  大厨
So why don't you get cooking, cook?
大厨
Cook?
我非拿你脸下厨不可
I'll cook your face
你先别急
Easy, Tiger
配合一下  省得被他们举报
Let's play along so they don't report us
好吧
Fine
快来吃吧
Come and get it
你们这群混蛋
You lousy punks
你该不会真要
You're not really gonna
给他们吃这种腐烂海霸糊吧
feed them this putrid chum, are you?
当然要
Sure
污染营友
Polluting campers
总比污染湖水更环保吧
is more environmentally conscious
than polluting the lake
对吧  面条呆脑
Right, noodle brain?
呆脑面条
Brain noodles
我突然就不饿了
Suddenly, I'm not hungry
我也不饿
Me neither
谁想打排球
Does anybody want to play some volleyball?
那是当然要的了
Does a one-legged duck swim in circles?
等等我
Wait for me
咪
Meep
恶心
Yuck
玷污到我了
I've been sullied
得去洗个澡
I need a shower
等等
Wait
别洗澡
Don't shower
你就没看过恐怖片吗
Have you never seen a horror movie?
怪客会抓走你的
The Creeper will get you
我落单了
I'm alone
一样也违反了恐怖片的规矩
That's against the horror movie rules too
咪咪咪
Meep, meep, meep
咪
Meep
淋浴
真舒服
That's good
这块我向来都刷不到
I can never get back there
哈维  是你吗
Harvey, is that you?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
好干净
So clean--
干净得不得了
so terrifyingly clean
好干净
So clean
受困的这个营地脏乱差
While we're stuck at this dirty camp
排球冠军会花落谁家
who's gonna be the volleyball champ?
各就位
Get ready
我这次发球叫
I call this serve the
先生  可不可以请你把球还回来呢
"Hey, Mister, can we get our ball back, please?"
局面会很小气
That's gotta stingy
往回打
Hit 'em back
狠狠暴击
Whack attack
小船队加油
Let's go, Dinghies
我来捡
I got it
耍小聪明是吧
A wise guy, eh?
你笑什么笑
What you laughing at?
我之所以笑  是因为树林在笑
I'm just laughing because the woods are laughing
阿莫呢
Where's Mo?
很明显是被我烧到了
Obviously, incinerated by me
你应该是想说吓到吧
I think you mean "intimidated"
对
Yeah
随便
Whatever
我们还是要摧毁你  兄弟
We're still gonna destroy you, dude
高个  你来替补
Hey, Tall Tail, you're subbed in
快点啊  高个
Come on, Tall Tail
努力加把劲
pull up your socks
打到球  胜利得
Smash that ball, win it all
体育一定行
Let's go Jocks
我这次发球叫  深度撞击
I call this serve Deep Impact
勉强打中而已
Barely hit me
我去捡
I'll get it
我跟你一起
I'll come with you
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
住游艇小屋的那几个
the Yacht Cabin
凯文
Kevin
海加护士
Nurse Helga
凤尾鱼
the Anchovies
海霸王
Bubble Bass
就连体育健将也都神秘消失了
and now the jocks have all mysteriously disappeared
多半是到哪个地方去玩了吧
They're probably just somewhere having fun
多半是入土了
Somewhere in their graves
肯定有个非常像样
I'm sure there's a perfectly good
合情合理  有科学依据的解释
highly reasonable
scientifically-proven explanation
能说明他们为什么消失
for their disappearances
更何况体育健将又没有全都不见
And besides, not all the jocks are gone
高个还
Tall Tail is still--
我的天啊
jumping flapjacks
他也消失了
He's gone
珊瑚营怪客又下手了
The Kamp Creeper strikes again
团圆会不有趣了
This reunion's not so fun
下一个中招的向来都是啦啦队员
The cheerleaders always the next one
给我一个哭
Give me a C-R-Y
未完待续